Phone: (646) 498-6814

e-mail: mickael.avedissian@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Internationally focused with a Masters Degree in Information Technology, and clear goals for furthering a career within a North American setting. Solid background in computer science and programming, with a specialty in network management and system administration. An expert with large customer-focused networks with practical experience in high pressure, system crises situations. Dedicated and hard working professional, skilled in developing and implementing many kinds of databases and computer scripts.

#### **Career History**

**International Securities Exchange (ISE)**, New York, USA Senior Application Support Analyst, January 2013 - Current

Team lead in System Deployment Automation (SDA)

- Implemented the software deployment for Windows applications via Puppet
- Responsible to help maintain the Puppet source code
- Contributing on a daily basis to the Production environment
- Team leader in the Windows application deployment
- Communicate and contribute on a daily basis with the Engineering team
- Manage the different environments (Prod, QA, OAT) via Puppet
- Manage Pull Requests and Issues via Github.com

Team lead in the Application Support Group

- Gain responsibilities towards the Application Support Group daily operations
- Responsible for application maintenance and upgrade
- Support both end of day, and start of day processes

# **International Securities Exchange (ISE)**, New York, USA Application Support Analyst, December 2010 – December 2012

- Manage installation and configuration of application software for production environments on multiple platforms on Test and Production environments
- Work on multiple projects simultaneously, sometimes in a leadership role
- Participate in design meetings, implementation planning process, and the management of production issues
- Make several daily modifications to support customers' business and technical specifications
- Perform operational acceptance tests before changes are rolled out
- Deploy application software and configuration changes across all Production and Test environments
- Create and execute operational test plans/scripts/cases based on technical and business requirements for trading applications and market operations support tools using Shell scripting and Perl when needed.

- Support the execution of unit, acceptance, performance, capacity, regression and system failover testing on back-end components using manual and automated test procedures
- Support scheduled weekend testing of Production level systems and applications
- Provide application and system support for several internal departments including Computer Operations, SQM, Product Management and Technology Member Services
- Provide application and environment administration of a complex trading systems
- Troubleshoot and diagnose systems problems; install and configure fixes for applications running on Red Hat Linux and Windows platforms
- Provide online and offline Level II support for the trading systems
- Analyze cause of production problems and develop methods for improvement
- Manage open trading systems issues with customers and vendors
- Emergency release handling Research and selection of products to fulfill project requirements.
- Working daily with Mysql Cluster, MS SQL, Windows Server 2008, Failover Cluster Manager, Internet Information Service Manager (IIS), Red Hat Enterprise 5.5, Shell Script and Perl.

# Société Générale, New York, USA

# Front and Middle Office Support (Technologies Department), June 2009-November 2010

- Production support level 1 & 2 and monitoring for Front and Middle Office applications for Equity Program Trading Desk.
- Support on Fidessa FTW, FDA, FixBox GUI, Tibco Interfaces and a proprietary Java application.
- First point of contact for traders and others to respond and investigate trading system issues.
- Handle configuration, releases, installations and monitoring of trading applications.
- Communicate with other members of Support teams to ensure consistency of information for problem resolution.
- Communicate with external parties such as exchanges and vendors.
- Coordinating infra-structure teams input to maintain the production platform
- Tracking and follow up issues to ensure fast resolution.
- Writing Database query for data extraction on Sybase and Oracle.
- Implementing Shell scripts for Database Update and data monitoring.
- Coordinating with support teams in Europe and Asia for problem resolution
- Working on different operating systems (Sun OS / Linux / Windows)

#### Synten, Clamart, France

# System Administrator, April 2006- May 2009

- Working in Linux/Windows, Apache, PHP, Shell script, HTML, MySQL
- Responsible for maintaining more than 200 servers, which host web sites and web applications for 120 clients
- Responsible for the Research and Development pole of the company
- Perform Virtualization with Xen
- Creation of a Flash video conversion platform
- Perform network installation, and tests that the system is perfectly working
- Undertook complex Datacenter relocation, ensuring minimal downtime
- On call 24/7 in order to respond quickly to any problems with software or hardware malfunctions

# Epitech, Le Kremlin-bicêtre, France

### System Administrator, Dec. 2004-Mars 2006

- Gained experience with BSD/Solaris/Linux/Windows, Cisco and HP
- Led group project for the installation of a video surveillance system over IP
- On call 24/7 to maintain system, and handle crash situations

#### **Education**

Masters of Information Technology, Epitech – Kremlin-bicêtre, France 20

2003-2008

- Programming in C, Perl, PHP, HTML, Shell script
- Network security systems courses
- Led, organized and planed a group for the school's projects
- Both English and French Masters curriculum; projects exclusively in English

Bachelor of Information Technology, Epitech - Kremlin-bicêtre, France 2006 Baccalauréat, Lycée Technique Privé Saint Nicolas - Paris, France 2002

#### Languages

- French: native
- English: proficient both in conversation and business usage
- Spanish: basic conversational capability

## **Personal Interest**

Member of a Volley-ball team, traveling, sailing, computers, music, movies

#### References

Available upon request